A Guide to the Papers of the Dean of Students, University of Virginia, 1977-2006
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Dean of Students, University of Virginia 1977-2006
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-18/2/1.064
ca. 5358 items in 23 Hollinger boxes, ca. 10 linear feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions apply to personally identifiable student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
These records were transferred to Special Collections through Rhonda F. Saunders, Office of the Dean of Students, on October 6, 2006.
Scope and Content
These papers consist of the administrative and topical files of the Office of Dean of Student, ca. 5,358 items (23 Hollinger boxes, ca.10 linear feet) 1977-2006.
The papers consist of administrative and topical files pertinent to student life at the University of Virginia. Subjects include the Ernest H. Ern Award; the First Year Resource Center; the Gray-Carrington Award; the Gus Bladgden Committee; the Jefferson Literary and Debating Society; the Lawn Organizing Committee; Orientation; Parents Program funding; the Public Service and Outreach Commission; the Stillfried/Godsey Award; Student Council; the Student Enrollment Services Process Owners' Group; Student Organizations and Programs Steering Committee; substance abuse; University Committee on Public Art; University Committee on Information Technology; Asian American studies; Asian Pacific American Heritage Month; yearly Asian Pacific American Leadership Training Institutes; Asian Prospectives' days; Asian Student Union; Charting Diversity including roundtables and national information; Committee on Asian Cultures; DiAPAson; East Coast Asian American Student Union Conference; Filipino-American National Historical Society; Monroe Society; Peer Advising Family Network; Hurricane Katrina; Kaleidoscope Center; Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Resource Center; Phi Eta Sigma; Sexual Assault Board; Sexual Assault Judicial Review; student life at peer institutions; and the Peer Advising Family Network.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in four series, Series I: Papers of the Office of Dean of Students (Boxes 1-5); Series II: Asian/Asian Pacific American Files (Boxes 6-16); Series III: Papers of the Senior Associate Dean of Students Shamim Sisson (Boxes 17-21); and Series IV: Restricted Files (Boxes 22-23).
Contents List
- Series I: Papers of the Office of Dean of Students (Box-folder 1:1-5:5)
  - 1999-2000 Apple Grant Proposal, 2 items (Box-folder 1:2)
  - 1998-2002 Board of Visitors, 26 items (Box-folder 1:2)
  - 2000-2002 Class Councils, 21 items (Box-folder 1:3)
  - 2001-2002 Ernest H. Ern Award, 28 items (Box-folder 1:4)
  - 1996-1998 First Year Resource Center, 12 items (Box-folder 1:5)
  - 1998-2001 First Year Resource Center Advisory Board, 10 items (Box-folder 1:6)
  - 1997-2000 Gray-Carrington Award, 26 items (Box-folder 1:7)
  - 1999-2003 Gus Blagden Committee, 76 items (Box-folder 1:8)
  - 1998-2000 Honor System Review Commission, 4 items (Box-folder 1:9)
  - 1999-2002 Inter-Fraternity Council, 10 items (Box-folder 1:10)
  - 1997-1999 Internet Abuse Team, 15 items (Box-folder 1:11)
  - 1999-2000 Inter-Sorority Council, 11 items (Box-folder 1:12)
  - 1994-2001 Jefferson Literary and Debating Society, 47 items (Box-folder 2:1)
  - 2000-2002 Lawn Organizing Committee, 55 items (Box-folder 2:2)
  - 1983-2000 Lawn Steering Committee, 25 items (Box-folder 2:3)
  - 1999-2001 Leadership Summer Program, 5 items (Box-folder 2:4)
  - 1999 NIAAA Grant Proposal, regarding alcohol use of students, 2 items (Box-folder 2:5)
  - 1999-2000 Off-Grounds Safety Committee, 23 items (Box-folder 2:6)
  - 1999 Orientation, 42 items (Box-folder 2:7)
  - 2000-2001 Orientation, 41 items (Box-folder 2:8)
  - 2000-2001 Parents Program Funding, 43 items (Box-folder 3:1)
  - 2002-2003 Parents Program Funding, 13 items (Box-folder 3:2)
  - 1999 Public Service and Outreach Commission Planning, 19 items (Box-folder 3:3)
  - 2000 January-March Public Service and Outreach Commission Planning, 17 items (Box-folder 3:4)
  - 2000 April-September Public Service and Outreach Commission Planning, 23 items (Box-folder 3:5)
  - 1999-2000 Safety Concerns, 50 items (Box-folder 3:6)
  - 1998-2002 Stillfried/Godsey Award, 37 items (Box-folder 4:1)
  - 1999-2003 Student Council, 43 items (Box-folder 4:2)
  - 2000-2002 Student Enrollment Services Process Owners' Group, 53 items (Box-folder 4:3)
  - 2001 December-2002 March Student Organizations and Programs Steering Committee, 13 items (Box-folder 4:4)
  - 2002 April-2003 January Student Organizations and Programs Steering Committee, 20 items (Box-folder 4:%)
  - 1996-2000 Substance Abuse, 49 items (Box-folder 4:6)
  - 2001-2002 University Committee on Public Art, 36 items (Box-folder 5:1)
  - 1999 University Committee on Information Technology, 29 items (Box-folder 5:2)
  - 2000 University Committee on Information Technology, 6 items (Box-folder 5:3)
  - 2000 October-November University Committee on Information Technology, 4 items (Box-folder 5:4)
  - 1998 Year 2000 Compliance, 26 items (Box-folder 5:5)
- Series II: Asian/Asian Pacific American Files (Box-folder 5:6-16:9)
  - n.d. Academic Readings, 12 items (Box-folder 5:6)
  - 1990-2002 Academic Readings, 16 items (Box-folder 5:7)
  - 1982-1999 Affirmative Action, 22 items (Box-folder 6:1)
  - 2004 AMEL 302 - Class E-mails, 4 items (Box-folder 6:2)
  - 2004 AMEL 302 - Class Notes, 18 items (Box-folder 6:3)
  - 2004 AMEL 302 - Readings, 2 items (Box-folder 6:4)
  - 2004 AMEL 302 - Student Papers, 3 items (Box-folder 6:5)
  - 2004 AMEL 302 - Syllabus, 3 items (Box-folder 6:6)
  - 1998-2000 AMEL 493 - Asian American Studies Independent Research -Models, 53 items (Box-folder 6:7)
  - 2000 AMEL 493 - Conference, 10 items (Box-folder 6:8)
  - 2000 AMEL 493 - Correspondence, 44 items (Box-folder 6:9)
  - 2000 AMEL 493 - Curriculum, 39 items (Box-folder 6:10)
  - 2000 AMEL 493 - Retreat, 5 items (Box-folder 6:11)
  - 2002-2003 APA - Programming Schedule, 2 items (Box-folder 7:1)
  - 2003 Argument Newsletters, 2 items (Box-folder 7:2)
  - 2004-2005 Asian and Asian Pacific American Alumni Network, 12 items (Box-folder 7:3)
  - 2002 Asian and Asian Pacific American Film, 5 items (Box-folder 7:4)
  - 1999-2002 Asian and Asian Pacific Art, 8 items (Box-folder 7:5)
  - 2001 Asian American Programming Budget, 5 items (Box-folder 7:6)
  - 1977 Asian Americans and Litigation, 2 items (Box-folder 7:7)
  - 1988-1993 Asian American Student Survey, 7 items (Box-folder 7:8)
  - 2000 Asian American Studies Program - Notes, 1 item (Box-folder 7:9)
  - 2001-2002 Asian Leadership Council, 1 item (Box-folder 7:10)
  - 2004-2005 Asian Pacific American Graduate Student Colloquium, 3 items (Box-folder 7:11)
  - 1998-2000 Asian Pacific American Heritage Month, 48 items (Box-folder 7:12)
  - 2000-2001 Asian Pacific American Heritage Month, 19 items (Box-folder 7:13)
  - 2002-2006 Asian Pacific American Heritage Month, 6 items (Box-folder 7:14)
  - 1998-2005 Asian Pacific American Leadership Training Institute, 75 items (Box-folder 7:15)
  - 2001-2002 Asian Pacific American Leadership Training Institute - Applications, 45 items (Box-folder 8:1)
  - [1996-2001] Asian Pacific American Leadership Training Institute - Articles, 19 items (Box-folder 8:2)
  - 1998 Asian Pacific American Leadership Training Institute - Development, 13 items (Box-folder 8:3)
  - 2001 Asian Pacific American Leadership Training Institute - Evaluations, 77 items (Box-folder 8:4)
  - 2003 Asian Pacific American Leadership Training Institute - Evaluations, 49 items (Box-folder 8:5)
  - 1998-1999 Asian Pacific American Leadership Training Institute - Planning, 43 items (Box-folder 8:6)
  - [1993-1999] Asian Pacific American Leadership Training Institute - Readings, 32 items (Box-folder 8:7)
  - 1999 Asian Pacific American Leadership Training Institute - Responses and Notes, 111 items (Box-folder 9:1)
  - 1998-2005 Asian Pacific American - Miscellaneous, 15 items (Box-folder 9:2)
  - [1996-2005] Asian Pacific American - Newsletters, 5 items (Box-folder 9:3)
  - 2002-2003 Asian Pacific American Resource Guide, 1 item (Box-folder 9:4)
  - 1990-1991 Asian Prospectives' Day, 46 items (Box-folder 9:5)
  - 1992-1993 Asian Prospectives' Day, 81 items (Box-folder 9:6)
  - [1989-1990] Asian Student Union, 46 items (Box-folder 9:7)
  - 1990 September-1991 April Asian Student Union, 37 items (Box-folder 9:8)
  - 1994-1996 Asian Student Union - Allocations, 5 items (Box-folder 9:9)
  - 1997-1999 Asian Student Union - Allocations, 13 items (Box-folder 10:1)
  - 1993-2000 Asian Student Union - Constitution, 15 items (Box-folder 10:2)
  - 2004-2005 Award - Asian/Asian Pacific Organization of the Year, 10 items (Box-folder 10:3)
  - 2001 Beyond Black and White, 2 items (Box-folder 10:4)
  - 2003-2004 Budget, 1 item (Box-folder 10:5)
  - 2003-2006Cavalier Daily, regarding diversity, 6 items (Box-folder 10:6)
  - 1999-2000 Charting Diversity - Budget, 14 items (Box-folder 10:7)
  - 2000-2001 Charting Diversity - Community Roundtable, 1 item (Box-folder 10:8)
  - 2000 Charting Diversity - Curriculum and Pedagogy, 3 items (Box-folder 10:9)
  - 2000 Charting Diversity - Diversity Survey, 3 items (Box-folder 10:10)
  - 2000-2001 Charting Diversity - Faculty and Staff Involvement, 12 items (Box-folder 10:11)
  - 2000 Charting Diversity - General, 16 items (Box-folder 10:12)
  - 2001 Marcj 1 Charting Diversity - Governance, 1 item (Box-folder 10:13)
  - 1999-2000 Charting Diversity - National Diversity Roundtable, 46 items (Box-folder 10:14)
  - 2000-2001 Charting Diversity - Physical Space and Environment, 6 items (Box-folder 10:15)
  - 1998-1999 Charting Diversity - Planning Conference, 7 items (Box-folder 10:16)
  - 2000-2001 Charting Diversity - Policy and Procedure, 7 items (Box-folder 11:1)
  - 2001 March 1 Charting Diversity - Recruitment, 1 item (Box-folder 11:2)
  - 1999-2000 Charting Diversity - Roundtables, 34 items (Box-folder 11:3)
  - 2000-2001 Charting Diversity - Roundtables, 40 items (Box-folder 11:4)
  - 2000-2001 Charting Diversity - Student Development, 6 items (Box-folder 11:5)
  - 1987-1989 Committee on Asian Cultures, 122 items (Box-folder 11:6)
  - 1989 April-July Committee on Asian Cultures, 28 items (Box-folder 11:7)
  - 1989 August-September Committee on Asian Cultures, 75 items (Box-folder 11:8)
  - 1989 October-1991 February Committee on Asian Cultures, 43 items (Box-folder 12:1)
  - 2004-2005 DiAPAson - Meeting, 14 items (Box-folder 12:2)
  - 2005 DiAPAson - Registration, 28 items (Box-folder 12:3)
  - 2002 Discussion - Abercrombie & Fitch Issue, 6 items (Box-folder 12:4)
  - 2002-2004 East Coast Asian American Student Union Conference, 38 items (Box-folder 12:5)
  - 1996-2004 East Coast Asian American Student Union - Hmongs, 16 items (Box-folder 12:6)
  - 1990-1992 Filipino-American National Historical Society, 37 items (Box-folder 12:7)
  - 2004 Filipino Health Community Advisory Committee, 6 items (Box-folder 12:8)
  - 2001 January-February Hiring, Promotion, and Retention Round-table, 4 items (Box-folder 12:9)
  - 2004 June 6-11 Leadership 2004, 16 items (Box-folder 12:10)
  - 1988-1990 Monroe Society, 58 items (Box-folder 13:1)
  - 1991-1993 Monroe Society, 85 items (Box-folder 13:2)
  - [1988-2006] News Clippings - Diversity Issues, 64 items (Box-folder 13:3)
  - 1996-2000 Organization of Young Filipino Americans, 23 items (Box-folder 13:4)
  - 2003-2005 Peer Advising Family Network - Advisor Applications, 37 items (Box-folder 13:5)
  - 2003-2004 Peer Advising Family Network - Advisor Interviews, 22 items (Box-folder 13:6)
  - 2000 Peer Advising Family Network - Advisor Reports - Folder 1 of 2, 78 items (Box-folder 13:7)
  - 2000 Peer Advising Family Network - Advisor Reports - Folder 2 of 2, 78 items (Box-folder 13:8)
  - 2001 Peer Advising Family Network - Advisor Reports, 128 items (Box-folder 14:1)
  - 2003 Peer Advising Family Network - Advisor Reports, 110 items (Box-folder 14:2)
  - 2004 Peer Advising Family Network - Advisor Reports, 35 items (Box-folder 14:3)
  - 2005 Peer Advising Family Network - Advisor Reports, 54 items (Box-folder 14:4)
  - 2002 Peer Advising Family Network - Brochure, 4 items (Box-folder 14:5)
  - 2002-2004 Peer Advising Family Network - Evaluations, 39 items (Box-folder 14:6)
  - 2000-2001 Peer Advising Family Network - List of Advising Families, 1 item (Box-folder 14:7)
  - 2005-2006 Peer Advising Family Network - Manual, 1 item (Box-folder 14:8)
  - 2002-2005 Peer Advising Family Network - Meetings, 48 items (Box-folder 15:1)
  - 1990-2006 Peer Advising Family Network - Miscellaneous, 8 items (Box-folder 15:2)
  - 2001 Peer Advising Family Network - Recruitment, 5 items (Box-folder 15:3)
  - 2000-2005 Peer Advising Family Network - Resources, 46 items (Box-folder 15:4)
  - 1999-2005 Peer Advising Family Network - Retreats, 16 items (Box-folder 15:5)
  - 2000-2001 Peer Advising Family Network - Student Information, 15 items (Box-folder 15:6)
  - 2003-2004 Peer Advising Family Network - Student Information - Folder 1 of 2, 41 items (Box-folder 15:7)
  - 2003-2004 Peer Advising Family Network - Student Information - Folder 2 of 2, 37 items (Box-folder 15:8)
  - 2005 Peer Advising Family Network - Sweatshirts, 3 items (Box-folder 15:9)
  - 1997-2004 Program Flyers, 30 items (Box-folder 16:1)
  - 1990-1999 Publications, 7 items (Box-folder 16:2)
  - 2000-2005 Publications, 13 items (Box-folder 16:3)
  - 2001 Religion - September 11 th and Discrimination, 12 items (Box-folder 16:4)
  - 2005 South Asian Awareness Network, 11 items (Box-folder 16:5)
  - 2003-2005 Strategic Planning, 4 items (Box-folder 16:6)
  - 2002-2003 Student Life - Strategic Planning, 23 items (Box-folder 16:7)
  - 1993 November "Survey of Multicultural Experiences and Attitudes of Undergraduates at the University of Virginia" Report, (1 item) (Box-folder 16:8)
  - 1988 October "The Economic Status of Americans of Asian Descent: An Exploratory Investigation" Report, 1 item (Box-folder 16:9)
- Series III: Papers of the Senior Associate Dean of Students Shamim Sisson (Box-folder 17:1-21:13)
  - 1985 May 1 Ad Hoc Committee on Judicial Reform Final Recommendations, 1 item (Box-folder 17:1)
  - 1989-1995 Ad Hoc Committee on Sexual Assault, 11 items (Box-folder 17:2)
  - 2004-2005 Bias Incidents - Implementation Team, 7 items (Box-folder 17:3)
  - 1991 February 13 Black Fraternal Council - Founding Document, 1 item (Box-folder 17:4)
  - 2001-2002 Dean-on-Call Manual, 2 items (Box-folder 17:5)
  - 2002-2003 Dean-on-Call Manual, 1 item (Box-folder 17:6)
  - 2000-2001 Dean-on-Call Resources, 10 items (Box-folder 17:7)
  - 2003-2004 First Year Seminar, 20 items (Box-folder 17:8)
  - 1998-1999 Hispanic/Latino Programming, 8 items (Box-folder 17:9)
  - 2005 Septmber-December Hurricane Katrina, 37 items (Box-folder 18:1)
  - 2004-2005 Kaleidoscope Advisory Committee, 15 items (Box-folder 18:2)
  - 2004-2005 Kaleidoscope Center, 61 items (Box-folder 18:3)
  - 2003-2004 Kaleidoscope Center - Founding, 55 items (Box-folder 18:4)
  - 2004 Kaleidoscope Center - Planning Committee, 14 items (Box-folder 18:5)
  - 2003-2005 Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Resource Center, 26 items (Box-folder 18:6)
  - 2004-2006 Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Resource Center Coordinator, 16 items (Box-folder 18:7)
  - [1989-2005] News Clippings, regarding diversity, 35 items (Box-folder 18:8)
  - 1994-1999 Office of Dean of Students - Assessment Project, 8 items (Box-folder 19:1)
  - 2000-2002 Office of Dean of Students - Assessment Project, 4 items (Box-folder 19:2)
  - 2003 Parents as Partners Program, 1 item (Box-folder 19:3)
  - 2000-2004 Phi Eta Sigma, 42 items (Box-folder 19:4)
  - 2003 Second Year Seminar, 14 items (Box-folder 19:5)
  - 1989-2003 Sexual Assault Board, 15 items (Box-folder 19:6)
  - 2003-2004 Sexual Assault Board, 12 items (Box-folder 19:7)
  - 2004-2005 Sexual Assault Board, 17 items (Box-folder 19:8)
  - 1990-1992 Sexual Assault Education Coordinator, 4 items (Box-folder 19:9)
  - 1991-1996 Sexual Assault - Handouts, 10 items (Box-folder 20:1)
  - 1990-1991 Sexual Assault Judicial Review, 7 items (Box-folder 20:2)
  - 1990-1997 Sexual Assault Judicial Review - Correspondence, 61 items (Box-folder 20:3)
  - 1990-1991 Sexual Assault Judicial Review - Dean of Students Office, 7 items (Box-folder 20:4)
  - 1990-1991 Sexual Assault Judicial Review - Meeting Notes, 22 items (Box-folder 20:5)
  - 1991-1992 Sexual Assault Judicial Review - Meeting Notes, 7 items (Box-folder 20:6)
  - 1991-1994 Sexual Assault Judicial Review - Membership, 8 items (Box-folder 20:7)
  - 1991 January-May Sexual Assault Judicial Review - Name Change of Committee, 4 items (Box-folder 20:8)
  - 1991 Sexual Assault Judicial Review - Procedures Brochure, 7 items (Box-folder 20:9)
  - 1991 Sexual Assault Judicial Review - Slander suits against victims, 9 items (Box-folder 20:10)
  - 1990-1991 Sexual Assault Judicial Review - Statute of Limitations, 4 items (Box-folder 20:11)
  - 1979-1993 Sexual Assault Procedure for Cases, 23 items (Box-folder 20:12)
  - 1995 October-1997 August Sexual Assault Procedure for Cases, 10 items (Box-folder 20:13)
  - 1997 September-1998 April Sexual Assault Procedure for Cases, 17 items (Box-folder 20:14)
  - 1998 Sexual Assault Procedure for Cases - Discussion, 10 items (Box-folder 21:1)
  - 1997 Sexual Assault Protocol, 8 items (Box-folder 21:2)
  - 1989 Sexual Assault Services Assessment, 2 items (Box-folder 21:3)
  - 1994-2001 Solicitation and Student Organization Fundraising, 13 items (Box-folder 21:4)
  - 2003-2004 Student Contacts, 5 items (Box-folder 21:5)
  - 1998-2003 Student Government, 5 items (Box-folder 21:6)
  - 2001-2004 Student Life, 29 items (Box-folder 21:7)
  - 2002-2003 Student Life Deans' Meeting, 21 items (Box-folder 21:8)
  - 2004-2005 Student Life - Peer Institutions, 29 items (Box-folder 21:9)
  - 2003 November Student Life - Retreat, 6 items (Box-folder 21:10)
  - 2004-2005 Student Life - Strategic Planning, 32 items (Box-folder 21:11)
  - 1990-1992 Task Force for the Prevention of Sexual Assault, 13 items (Box-folder 21:12)
  - 2001-2003 Transportation and Park Advisory Committee, 12 items (Box-folder 21:13)
- Series 4: Restricted Files (Box-folder 22:1-24:7)
  - 2004 AMEL 302 - Student Papers, 3 items (Box-folder 22:1)
  - 2001-2002 Ernest H. Ern Award, 9 items (Box-folder 22:2)
  - 2000 Gray-Carrington Award - Letters of Nomination, 41 items (Box-folder 22:3)
  - 2001 Gray-Carrington Award - Letters of Nomination, 53 items (Box-folder 22:4)
  - 2002 Gray-Carrington Award - Letters of Nomination, 83 items (Box-folder 22:5)
  - 2000 Gus Blagden Room Committee - Letters of Nomination, 85 items (Box-folder 22:6)
  - 2001 February-March Gus Blagden Room Committee - Letters of Nomination, 46 items (Box-folder 22:7)
  - 2001 March-April Gus Blagden Room Committee - Letters of Nomination, 88 items (Box-folder 22:8)
  - 2002 Gus Blagden Room Committee - Letters of Nomination, 63 items (Box-folder 23:1)
  - 2000-2002 Incident Reports, 42 items (Box-folder 23:2)
  - 2002-2003 Peer Advising Family Network - Applications, 36 items (Box-folder 23:3)
  - 1999-2000 Peer Advising Family Network - Student Information, 28 items (Box-folder 23:4)
  - 2000-2001 Peer Advising Family Network - Student Information - Folder 1 of 2, 55 items (Box-folder 23:5)
  - 2000-2001 Peer Advising Family Network - Student Information - Folder 2 of 2, 45 items (Box-folder 23:6)
  - 1999-2000 Stillfried/Godsey Award, 12 items (Box-folder 23:7)